Guide to the American Printing History Association records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
American Printing History Association Records,
1972-2012
American Printing History Association.
13.48 linear feet (19 document boxes, 14 flat boxes, 1 record storage carton, and 1 card file box).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
6766907
MS#1458
The American Printing History Association (APHA) was founded in 1974 to foster and to promote interest in the history of printing, especially American printing, and in the preservation of its artifacts. The records document the activities of both the national organization and its local chapters, and include material on the board of directors, bylaws, chapters, committees, conferences, finance, meetings, membership, publications, and special projects.
Historical Note
The American Printing History Association (APHA) was founded as the result of a proposal published by Walter Kubelius in his column, "The Printing Whirl," in the 1971 issue of Printing Impressions. Kubelius proposed that an American Printing Historical Society should be founded to foster scholarship and to serve as a forum for the exchange of knowledge. At the time, it was thought that the society should be developed as an American chapter of the Printing Historical Society, which represents all aspects of the printing arts and industry worldwide. Although J. Ben Lieberman pursued this objective, it was ultimately decided that it would be too difficult to fit the new society's aims within those of the larger organization, and APHA was founded as an independent organization in May 1974.
APHA established an organizational structure that would serve its goals. There were four main components - the membership, local chapters, trustees and officers, and committees. APHA wanted to have a broad membership, and with it local chapters to organize ongoing activities. Committees would be used to handle specialized programs, and a national board of trustees and officers would serve to coordinate the local chapters and to pursue national and international projects that could not be handled at the chapter level.
APHA has four main organizational objectives: 1. To encourage the study of printing, especially American printing, in its whole range. 2. To produce and promote publications, exhibitions, conferences, lectures, and other functions so that information is exchanged. 3. To foster the development and maintenance of libraries and museums for the preservation of materials that relate to printing history. 4. To cooperate with others to recognize the central importance of printing to humanity.
Scope and Content
The APHA records document the activities of the national organization and its local chapters, and include annual reports, brochures, bylaws, budgets, clippings, correspondence, financial reports, legal documents, lists of officers and members, memoranda, minutes, notes, press releases, programs, and speeches.
The records of the national organization include documentation of annual conferences, annual meetings, awards, the board of directors, bylaws, committees, conferences, finance, meetings, membership, publishing efforts, and special projects. Coverage is most complete for the activities of the board of directors, annual conferences, awards, and finances.
The chapter records are incomplete. There are no records related to the Chesapeake chapter, and and in many instances documentation is limited to newsletters and information on the founding of each chapter. The records of the New York Chapter are the most extensive for 1976-1996, and include announcements, bylaws, correspondence, financial records, meeting materials and minutes, lists of members and officers, and press releases.
The documentation of APHA is incomplete and haphazard. A filing system was created for existing records in 1981; as a result, most of the organization's early records were organized and preserved in the archives. The lack of a documentation system thereafter has created inconsistency and gaps in coverage of the organization's activities although high level organizations activities including annual conferences, the board of directors, and finances are well-documented in the records.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in five series.
Series I: Organizational Files, 1974-2008
Series II: Presidents' Files, 1972-2000
Subseries II.1: J. Ben Lieberman, 1972-1987
Subseries II.2: Martin Hutner, 1983-1998
Subseries II.3: Anne Anninger, 1998-2000
Subseries II.4: Paul Romaine, 2008-2012
Subseries II.5: Catherine Tyler Brody, 1974-2008
Subseries II.6: Irene Tichenor, 1984-2001
Series III: Chapter Files, 1975-2001
Subseries III.1: General, 1975-1987
Subseries III.2: New York, 1976-1996
Subseries III.3: Other Chapters, 1975-2001
Series IV: Publications, 1975-2002
Subseries IV.1: Catherine Brody, 1975-1985
Subseries IV.2: Printing History, 1978-1998
Subseries IV.3: Other Publications and Projects, 1975-2002
Series V: General Files, 1974-1998
Subjects
American Printing History Association.; Lieberman, J. Ben.; Printing--History.; Printing--United States--Societies, etc.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
[source of acquisition] Gift, Purchase, etc. date accn number
The archives of the American Printing History Association (APHA) were originally housed at the Columbia University School of Library Service, starting in the early 1980s
Related Material
The two major publications of APHA, Printing History and the APHA Newsletter, as well as published monographs, have been separately cataloged as part of the book collection of the Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
The American Printing History Association Collection, circa 1974-1983, is at the University of California at Santa Barbara. The collection contains bylaws, membership directories and information, flyers, conference notices and programs, and other mailings relating to activities of APHA, including the Southern California Chapter. These mainly consist of items sent to Hobart Skofield, an APHA member.
The J. Ben Lieberman Papers are at the University of Delaware. Lieberman was the founder and first president of APHA.
Finding aid in repository; folder level control.
- Series I: Organizational Files, 1974-2008
  This series contains files related to organizational functions and issues, arranged alphabetically by topic. It includes files on annual conferences, annual meetings, awards, the board of directors, bylaws, committees, finance, membership, and special projects. There is additional material related to these organizational activities in Series II: Presidents' Files and Series V: General Files. The records include annual reports, brochures, bylaws, budgets, clippings, correspondence, financial reports, membership lists, press releases, programs, and speeches.
  - Announcements and Communications to Members, 1974-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Meetings
    - Minutes, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - APHA Lieberman Speech, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Annual Meeting (Includes invoices and receipts), 1991-1994 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Martin Hutner’s Reports to Annual Meeting as Vice President for Membership--Related Material, 1991-1994 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1975, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Archives--Report and Recommendations for APHA Archives, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Awards
    - General
      - 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1982-2002 (4 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 1 to 3, 5)
    - APHA Annual Award, 1982 October 8 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      (Drafts of criteria)
    - APHA Award Speech, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 14)
      (by John Dreyfus)
    - APHA--L. Rostenberg Speech, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      (Award acceptance speech)
  - Board of Directors
    - General
      - Untitled, 1977-1982 (Box 6, Folder 15)
        (Includes board meeting minutes, annual reports, budgets, financial statements, notes, etc)
      - Untitled, 1983-1988 (Box 8, Folder 11 to 12)
        (Mainly outgoing memos from board members)
      - Jean Peters--Miscellaneous, 1974-1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
        (Includes reports, meeting minutes, memos, etc.)
      - Board Issues, 1982-1983, (3 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 4 to 6)
        (From Anna Lou Ashby)
      - AHPA Board, 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 3)
        (Includes board and nominating committee material.)
      - Renee, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 7)
        (Renee Weber was the Secretary of the Board. Includes meeting announcements, a budget, and membership statistics)
    - Board Nominations, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Directory of Officers, 1974-1981 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      (Includes copy of 1974 bylaws)
    - Meetings
      - Board Meetings, 1982-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 13 to 14)
      - Current Meetings Working Folder, 1983-1984) (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Meeting Announcement, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Minutes
        - 1974-1981, (3 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 5 to 7)
        - 1974-1981 (Box 8, Folder 15)
        - 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 16)
        - 1990 October-2005 (5 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 2 to 6)
          (See Also Nina Schneider’s board meeting materials)
        - Reports to, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Memoranda--Officers and Trustees of APHA, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 10)
        (Memos from the board secretary)
      - Nina Schneider’s Records
        - 2003 October 24-2006 April (11 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 1 to 11)
        - 2006 June-2007 April (4 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Brochures and Ephemera
    - Brochures and Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - circa 1976-1981 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - APHA Membership Brochure, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bylaws
    - 1974-1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - By-Laws, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Clippings
    - General, 1974-1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Publicity, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      (Clippings and articles)
  - Committees
    - Awards Committee, 1985-1993 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Committee on Committees, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Education, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Executive, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Finance, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Nominating
      - 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 1978, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - 1981 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Program Coordinating, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Relationships, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Conferences
    - Annual
      - First, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Second, 1977
        - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
          (Includes contact sheets)
        - Printing Paper Quarterly (Proceedings of the 2nd Annual Meeting), 1977 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Third, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Fourth, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Fifth, 1980
        - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
        - 1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
          (Announcement, only)
        - APHA Annual Conference Picture Set, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 22)
        - Keepsakes for APHA, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Sixth, 1981
        - 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - 1981 (Box 13, Folder 17)
          (Brochures. Includes 1988 brochure)
      - Seventh--Local Arrangements, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Eighth
        - Local Arrangements, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 7)
        - Eighth APHA Annual Conference Keepsake, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 6)
        - Annual Conference, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 13)
          (Includes copies of remarks, speeches)
        - APHA Conference, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 18)
          (Cathy Brody's report on)
      - Ninth--Local Arrangements, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Tenth, 1985
        - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - Program, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Eleventh-Thirteenth, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Twentieth Anniversary Conference, 1994
        - General (Box 12, Folder 7)
        - 1994 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - 1996 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - 1997-2001 (4 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 1 to 4)
      - 2003-2008 (8 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Annual Conference--Receipts, Invoices, 1991-1995 (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 1 to 2)
      (Includes other materials)
    - Brochures, 1983-1984, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence
    - Board Members, Trustees, Officers (Box 2, Folder 17)
      (Correspondence between officers, board members, and trustees)
    - Miscellaneous, 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      (Correspondence between members, and between members and officers)
    - Stu Dobson Incident, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      (Resignation of)
    - Vice Presidents of Publications
      - Steve O. Saxe, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - John B. Hench, 1982-1984 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Correspondence--Inactive, 1991-1995 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - General, 1983-1984 (2 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 2 to 3)
      - General, 1992-1993 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Fellowships
    - APHA Fellowship, 2007-2008 (2 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 5 to 6)
      (From Nina Schneider’s records)
  - Finances
    - General
      - APHA, 1978-1984 (Box 11, Folder 8)
        (Includes correspondence on treasury issues; appears to be the file of Catherine Brody)
      - General, 1979-2004 (4 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 1 to 4)
        (Includes treasurer’s reports and financial statements)
    - Reports
      - 1974-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 20 to 21)
      - 1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Tax Records
      - Form 990, 1974-1999 (3 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Forms 1096/1099-Misc, 1992-1995 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Founding, 1972-1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    (Includes copies of Lieberman's correspondence with David Chambers at the Printing Historical Society)
  - APHA Fundraiser--Sotheby’s Benefit Auction, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Logo Competition, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Membership
    - General
      - Membership, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - APHA Members, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Census, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Status
      - Charter Membership List, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Contributing Members, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Dues Paid Members (Box 2)
        - 1974-1976, (3 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 25 to 27)
        - 1977-1978, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Membership Renewal, 1991-1994 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Institutional Memberships (Charter), 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Invitees, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Lists of Lapsed Members, 1986-1997 (Box 31, Folder 9)
        (Includes 1986 Directory)
      - Subscribers, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Sustaining Members, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - 1974-1978, (7 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 7 to 13)
      - Claire Van Vliet, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Distribution, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      (Statistics for geographic distribution)
    - Membership Department, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Membership Drives, 1991-1999 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Membership Lists
      - APHA--Membership--Interests of Members, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Archives, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
        (Membership lists)
      - Membership Lists (by Committee Interests), 1975 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - APHA Archive, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 2)
        (Membership Lists)
    - APHA Questionnaires, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      (Survey responses and summary report)
  - Obituaries, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    (Only one, for Helen Macy)
  - Officers
    - Certification of
      - 1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - 1986 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Directory, 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Postal Service, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Press Releases, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Projects--Two Thirds Press, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Schwanenlied, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    (Memo on accomplishments of the first year, from MMS)
  - Tax Exemption-- Income Tax, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Series II: President's Files, 1972-2000
  - Subseries II.1: Ben Lieberman, 1972-1987
    J. Ben Lieberman was the founder and first president of APHA. His files include material on the founding and early organization of APHA. These records include bylaws, brochures, clippings, correspondence, legal documents, memoranda, minutes, speeches, and files on the board of directors, chapters, committees, conferences, finances, membership, projects, and publications.
    - APHA Copy Editing, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 21)
      (Correspondence of Elizabeth Lieberman)
    - Financial, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - APHA Speech/Handout Copies, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - APHA Oral History Permanent File, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - APHA Conference, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - APHA Nominating Committee, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - APHA NYC Membership Lists, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - APHA Founding, Charter, Members' Card Xeroxes, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - APHA Membership Lists, 1974-1977 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Census Forms, circa 1975 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Untitled, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - National APHA Board Meetings--Assorted Memos, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - APHA Board, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - APHA Basic Papers, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Philadelphia Chapter, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - APHA Current, 1975-1977 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - APHA Forms and Reprints, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - APHA Founding, 1972-1978 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - APHA IRS Tax Exempt, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - APHA Organizing, 1974-1980 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - APHA Board Business, 1974-1982 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - APHA Board Minutes, 1977-1982 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Untitled, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      (Clippings & press release on founding; brochure)
    - Untitled, 1973-1975 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      (Mainly correspondence)
    - APHA, 1974-1977 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Untitled, 1974-1975, (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 2 to 3)
    - APHA Journal, 1975-1979 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 1st Annual Meeting--Keepsake, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - APHA Funding, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - APHA Current, 1978-1982 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - APHA Re: Printing History Society (London), 1973-1976 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - APHA Conference on Ephemera, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - APHA Re: Open House: Quiet Afternoon, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Untitled, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      (Mostly related to the Goudy Society)
    - APHA Brochure, Undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - APHA Certificate of Incorporation, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - APHA Press Two-Thirds, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      (On the Two-Thirds Press Bicentennial Project)
    - Maryland Gazette (APHA), 1977 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - APHA Basic Information, 1975-1978 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Untitled, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      (Related to the founding of the Letterpress Society)
    - APHA, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - APHA Role, Undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - APHA, 1974-1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - APHA Letter/Working Papers, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Untitled, 1975-1977 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      (APHA)
    - APHA Basic Papers, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      (Includes papers on incorporation, PO Box, bank account, etc.)
    - APHA Conference, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - APHA, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      (List of officers, basic information for committee chairman, and material on the committee on committees)
    - APHA Membership, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      (Outgoing memos)
    - APHA New York Chapter, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - APHA By-laws, Incorporation, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - APHA Founders' Certificate, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - APHA Brochure, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - APHA Stationary, Undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - APHA Annual Meeting, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Untitled, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      (Related to the Two-Thirds Press Project)
    - APHA Artifacts, 1976, Undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - APHA, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      (Form letters, forms, clippings)
    - APHA Miscellany; Ben to Follow Up, Etc., 1974-1975 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Untitled, 1974-1978 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      (Correspondence, minutes, etc.)
    - APHA First Annual Meeting, 1975 January 22 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Monographs, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      ("A Pride of Printers" and the "Caxton Congress Announcement" were mailed to founding and charter members renewing membership for 1976)
    - Two-Thirds Press Handout, circa 1976 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - APHA Annual Meeting, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - APHA Conference, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - APHA Bicentennial, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - APHA Unsorted, 1981, Undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
      (Meeting notice; announcement of Smithsonian type revivals)
    - APHA First Annual Conference, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Audio Reel, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      (Second Annual Meeting. Includes address by Dr. Robert Leslie upon receipt of the first annual APHA award for Printing History)
  - Subseries II.2: Martin Hutner, 1983-1998
    Marvin Hutner was president of APHA in the mid to late 1990s. He had also served as Secretary and Vice-President for Membership for the organization. His files include bylaws, correspondence, minutes, reports, and material on annual meetings, the board of directors, chapters, committees, conferences, membership, and publications.
    - Untitled, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      (Correspondence)
    - 1) Awards Committee 2) Nominating Committee 3) Lieberman 4) Sharvard, 1989-1997 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Bylaws, 1983-1994 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Chapters, 1993-1995 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Conferences, 1989-1996 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Membership, 1991-1997 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Minutes
      - 1987-1996 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - 1987-1996 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Publications
      - A Type Miscellany, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - 1) Printing History 2) Newsletter, 1991-1995 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Additional Donations
      - Untitled, 1994-1996 (Box 19, Folder 4)
        (Board material and handwritten reports)
      - Untitled, 1997-1998 (Box 19, Folder 5)
        (President's report and material on the APHA board and the 1998 annual meeting.)
  - Subseries II.3: Anne Anninger, 1998-2000
    Anninger kept records related to her term as president in a chronological arrangement. These records include correspondence, financial reports, minutes, notes, and material related to the board of directors and APHA conferences.
    - 1998 January-1999 April, (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 16 to 17)
    - 1999 May-2000 January (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Subseries II.4: Paul Romaine Files, 2008-2012
    - Legal Files, 1992-2010 (Box 35)
    - Executive Secretary, 2011 (Box 35)
    - Annual Conference Files, 2008-2011, (4 Folders) (Box 35)
    - Board Reports and General Meeting Remarks, 2008-2011, (15 Folders) (Box 35)
      (These files, arranged chronologically, contain the agendas for each meeting, along with related correspondence and officer's reports. The files for the annual meetings also include drafts of Romain's presidential address.)
  - Subseries II.5: Catherine Tyler Brody Files, 1974-2008
    - Administrative Files, 1974-1984 (Box 35)
    - Correspondence and Administrative Files, 1975-2008 (Box 35)
    - Conference and Event Announcements, 1976-1986 (Box 35)
    - Printing News Article Drafts, 1984 (Box 35)
    - Award Speech- John Dreyfus
  - Subseries II.6: Irene Tichenor Files, 1984-2001
    - Printing History file,1998-2001 (Box 35)
    - Publications file, 2000-2001 (Box 35)
    - APHA Membership file, 2000-2001 (Box 35)
    - Advertising Manager file, 2001 (Box 35)